YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 6. Program: Series IV. Constituent Groups
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IV. CONSTITUENT GROUPS
  - Subseries C. Interracial/Racial Justice
    - "Colored" and "Interracial" Work, 1906-70
      - Publications
        - "Guide to Recording Reactions to Interracial Relationships," Leadership Services, 1957 (Box 538, Folder 9)
        - The Interracial Charter and Related Policy, 1955 (Box 538, Folder 10)
        - Interracial Cooperation: Helpful Suggestions Concerning Relations of White and Colored Citizens, circa 1920 (Box 538, Folder 11)
        - Interracial Education as it Affects Negro and White Relationships from the Point of View of Administrative Groups by Frances Harriet Williams, 1940 (Box 538, Folder 12)
        - Interracial Policies of the YWCA of the USA, edited by Dorothy I. Height, 1948 (Box 538, Folder 13)
        - Interracial Programs in Student YWCAs by Yolanda B. Wilkerson, 1948 (Box 538, Folder 14)
        - Outgrowths of the Interracial Structure of the YWCA: Current Administrative Practices by Cordella Winn and Frances Williams, 1934 (Box 538, Folder 15)
        - "Outline for a discussion course on Race Relations in the U.S.," 1923 (Box 538, Folder 16)
        - Personal Adventures in Race Relations by Esther Popel Shaw, 1946, 1948 (Box 538, Folder 17)
        - Program Papers for Today and Tomorrow. No. VIII: Nationality and Race are Important (various authors) and No. IX White Man's God? A Search for evidence of democracy and the Christian faith in interracial relations by Helen J. Wilkins, 1941 (Box 538, Folder 18)
        - Pudge Grows Up: Series of Meetings for High School Girls by Frances Williams and Wenonah Boyd Logan, 1936, [see Subseries D. for the complete "Pudge" series] (Box 538, Folder 19)
        - Step by Step with Interracial Groups by Dorothy I. Height, 1955 (Box 539, Folder 1)
        - Techniques in Race Relations by Frances Harriet Williams, 1937 (Box 539, Folder 2)
        - Three Meetings on Interracial Interests for Use in Discussion and Club Meetings by Gertrude Ware Bunce and Frances Williams, Program Series, 1934 (Box 539, Folder 3)
        - Two Interracial Studies: The Interracial Situation My Association Faces; The Negro in the United States of America by Frances Williams, 1934 (Box 539, Folder 4)
        - Toward Better Race Relations, Dothory {sic} Sabistan, Field Worker, Margaret Hiller, Editor, 1949 (Box 539, Folder 5)
        - The Work of Colored Women by Jane Olcott, 1919 (Box 539, Folder 6)
        - The World Best Known to a Negro Industrial Girl by Frances Harriet Williams, 1938 (Box 539, Folder 7)
        - Serials
          - Occasional Educational and Informational Papers, 1936-41 (Box 539, Folder 8-10)
      - Reference materials
        - 1917-29 (Box 539, Folder 11)
        - 1930-65, n.d. (Box 540, Folder 1-11)
      - Reports
        - Miscellaneous, 1909-58, n.d. (Box 541, Folder 1)
        - Secretaries'
          - Eva D. Bowles, 1915-31 (Box 541, Folder 2)
          - Marion Cuthbert, 1937-40 (Box 541, Folder 3)
          - Isobel C. Lawson, 1938-40 (Box 541, Folder 4)
          - Frances Harriet Williams, 1924-39 (Box 541, Folder 5)
          - Cordella Winn, 1930-38 (Box 541, Folder 6)
        - General Report on Work on Racial Inclusiveness, Sep 1956-Aug 1957 by Mary Jane Willett (Box 541, Folder 7)
        - Methods of Combating Discrimination: descriptive record submitted to the World's YWCA by the YWCA of the U.S.A., 1954 (Box 541, Folder 8-9)
        - The YWCA Strategy and Action in Methods of Combating Racial Discrimination, Triennium 1955-58, submitted to the World's YWCA (Box 541, Folder 10)
      - Studies
        - "A New Day for the Colored Woman Worker: A Study of Colored Women in Industry in New York City," directed by a joint committee with representatives from various organizations, funded by the YWCA, 1919 (Box 541, Folder 11)
        - Interracial Study, 1919 (compilation of answers to question #19 on 1918-19 annual reports of city associations) (Box 541, Folder 12)
        - Basic Civil Rights for Negroes
          - General, 1936, n.d. (Box 541, Folder 13)
          - Report "Fourteen Civil Rights Studies Made by Local Associations" by Frances Harriet Williams, 1938 (Box 541, Folder 14)
          - Reports from Associations
            - Durham, North Carolina, 1936 (Box 541, Folder 15)
            - Houston, Texas, 1936 (Box 541, Folder 16)
            - Indianapolis, Indiana, 1936 (Box 541, Folder 17)
            - Portland, Oregon, 1936 (Box 541, Folder 18)
            - Wichita, Kansas, 1936 (Box 541, Folder 19)
        - The Branch Study (Part II of The Standards Study), 1938 (Box 542, Folder 1)
        - The Extent of Certain Practices Relating to Racial Inclusiveness in Community YWCAs
          - Report, 1957 (Box 542, Folder 2)
          - Paper based on the study: "Experience in Interracial and Intercultural Practice" by Ruth Henderson, 1959 (Box 542, Folder 3)
        - Interracial Study
          - Commission to Gather Interracial Experiences (a.k.a. Interracial Commission), 1941-45 (Box 542, Folder 4)
          - Questionnaires, 1943 (Box 542, Folder 5)
          - Report: Interracial Practices in Community YWCAs and Recommendations, 1944 (Box 542, Folder 6)
          - Follow-up (aka "Rosenwald Study")
            - General, 1945-49, n.d. (Box 542, Folder 7)
            - Comments from Community Associations, 1944-45 (Box 542, Folder 8)
            - Report: Toward Better Race Relations, 1949 (Box 542, Folder 9)
      - Training
        - General, 1943-63 (Box 542, Folder 10)
        - Institute for Leadership in Intergroup Relations, Feb 1960 (Box 542, Folder 11)
        - Seminar on Intergroup Relations and School for Professional Workers, Lake Erie College, summer 1961 (Box 542, Folder 12)
        - Workshop on Racial Integration
          - Atlanta, Georgia, Dec 1965 (Box 542, Folder 13)
          - Norman, Oklahoma, Mar 1966 (Box 542, Folder 14)
    - "Racial Justice" Work, 1970-2001
      - General and History
        - General, 1970-99 (Box 543, Folder 1)
        - "Case Studies in Policy Progress: The Origins of the YWCA's Anti-Racism Campaign" by Barbara J. Nelson and Alissa Hummer, 1989 (Box 543, Folder 2)
        - Wingspread Conference, "Eliminating Racism: Building on YWCA Experience," 1977 (Box 543, Folder 3)
        - Working Woman magazine survey on diversity in the workplace, 1994-96 (Box 543, Folder 4)
        - Events
          - Black History Month celebrations at '600,' 1996, n.d. (Box 543, Folder 5)
          - Dorothy I. Height Tribute Dinner (YWCA and National Council of Negro Women, 5 Nov 1986 (Box 543, Folder 6)
          - Martin Luther King, Jr. Commemorations at '600,' 1985-96, n.d. (Box 543, Folder 7)
        - Reference materials, miscellaneous, 1970-74, n.d. (Box 543, Folder 8)
      - Committees
        - Racial Justice Core Group/Task Force, 1971-76 (Box 543, Folder 9-10)
        - Committee on Racial Integration/Racial Justice, 1970?-91 (Box 543, Folder 11)
        - Special Racial Justice Fund Committee, 1970 (Box 543, Folder 12)
      - Offices
        - Center for Racial Justice Center, Program Unit, 1971-77 (Box 543, Folder 13)
        - Office of Racial Justice, Executive Office
          - General, 1983-90 (Box 543, Folder 14)
          - Proposal to Kellogg Foundation to establish a Center for Valuing Diversity, 1992 (Box 543, Folder 15)
        - Office of Racial Justice and Human Rights
          - General, 1997-2000, n.d. (Box 543, Folder 16)
          - Job descriptions and search for Director, 1997-98 (Box 543, Folder 17)
          - Hate crimes
            - General, 1997-2000 (Box 543, Folder 18)
            - Response Kit, 1998 (Box 544, Folder 1)
          - Ku Klux Klan activity, 1998-99 (Box 544, Folder 2)
          - Violence Against Asian Americans, 1984-85 (Box 544, Folder 3)
      - American Indians
        - General, 1970-85 (Box 544, Folder 4)
        - American Indian Task Force, 1987 (Box 544, Folder 5)
        - Reference materials, miscellaneous, circa 1970-86 (Box 544, Folder 6-7)
      - Community and Student Associations
        - General, 1970-99 (Box 544, Folder 8)
        - California
          - Mid-Peninsula (Palo Alto), 1979 (Box 544, Folder 9)
          - Y-House, University of California at Berkeley: Black Women's Symposium for Action, Apr 1976 (Box 544, Folder 10)
        - Maryland, Greater Baltimore Area: Breakthrough: An Action Handbook, 1975 (Box 544, Folder 11)
      - Conferences, Consultations, and Convocations
        - National Conference of Black Women in the YWCA, 1970 (Box 544, Folder 12)
        - La Conferencia de Mujeres por la Raza, Houston, May 1971 (Box 544, Folder 12a)
        - Consultation of White Women in the YWCA, Oct 1972 (Box 544, Folder 13-14)
        - National Convocation on Racial Justice, Jun 1972
          - Planning, Dec 1971-Jun 1972 (Box 544, Folder 15-16)
          - Program and Participants (Box 544, Folder 17)
          - Post-Convocation material (Box 544, Folder 18)
          - Western Region Third World Coalition Workshop, Nov 1972 (Box 544, Folder 19)
        - National Consultation of Native American Women of the YWCA, Nov 1973 (Box 545, Folder 1)
        - Conferencia de Mujeres Puertorriqueñas, Jan 1974 (Box 545, Folder 2)
        - Southern Region Consultation of Third World Women, 1974 (Box 545, Folder 3)
        - Racial Justice Convocation "Toward a Racial Justice Agenda for the 21st Century," Feb 1990
          - General (Box 545, Folder 4)
          - Planning (Box 545, Folder 5)
          - Press Kit (Box 545, Folder 6)
          - Workshop Leader biographies (Box 545, Folder 7)
        - Racial Justice Conference, Apr 1999 (Box 545, Folder 8)
      - Mexican-American Women, 1970 (Box 545, Folder 9)
      - Programs
        - One Imperative: To Eliminate Racism Wherever it Exists and By Any Means Necessary
          - General, 1969-76, n.d. (Box 545, Folder 10-11)
          - Convention 1970 "One Imperative Convention" (Box 545, Folder 12)
          - Use of phrase "by any means necessary," 1970-71 (Box 545, Folder 13)
          - Briefing sessions for National Board and staff, 1970 (Box 545, Folder 14)
          - Action Audit for Change, [see also Action Audit for Change Process below]
            - Materials distributed at National Board and staff meeting, Sep 1976 (Box 545, Folder 15)
            - Phase I: The YWCA as an Institution packet, Dec 1970 (Box 545, Folder 16)
            - Phase I (copy 2) (Box 546, Folder 1)
            - Phase II: Community Audit packet, Dec 1973 (Box 546, Folder 2)
            - Resource Leadership Team, 1971 (Box 546, Folder 3)
            - The National Board and Its Work, 1973-79 (Box 546, Folder 4)
          - Institutes, Consultations, Workshops, and Meetings
            - General, 1970-71 (Box 546, Folder 5)
            - Consultation of Asian American Women, May 1971 (Box 546, Folder 6)
            - Institute on the Web of Racism and Child Development, May 1971 (Box 546, Folder 7)
            - Institute on the Web of Racism and the Communications Media, Apr 1971 (Box 546, Folder 8)
            - Institute on the Web of Racism and Housing, May 1971 (Box 546, Folder 9)
            - Institute on the Web of Racism and Poverty, May 1971 (Box 546, Folder 10)
            - Mid-Point Meeting, Jul 1971 (Box 546, Folder 11)
            - Workshop on Dance and Drama of Selected Minority Groups, Jul 1971 (Box 546, Folder 12)
          - Film, 1971 (Box 546, Folder 13)
        - Communications Institute (proposed), 1971 (Box 546, Folder 14)
        - Action Audit for Change workbooks, 1977, circa 1990, 1994 (Box 546, Folder 15)
        - Affirmative Action
          - General, 1973-2000, n.d. (Box 547, Folder 1)
          - "Affirmative Action Plan with Goals and Timetables and Utilization Analysis Charts," National Personnel and Labor Relations Department, 1978 (Box 547, Folder 2)
          - "YWCA Affirmative Action Guide to Equal Employment," Center for Racial Justice, n.d. and Jan 1979 revised (Box 547, Folder 3-5)
          - Affirmative Action Review Team, 1991, n.d. (Box 547, Folder 6)
          - "Women Speak on Affirmative Action" packet prepared for YWCAs in Washington state, 1998 (Box 547, Folder 7)
        - National Day of Commitment to Eliminate Racism
          - 1992-96 (Box 547, Folder 8)
          - 1997
            - General (Box 547, Folder 9)
            - Organizer's Kit (Box 547, Folder 10)
          - 1998
            - General (Box 547, Folder 11)
            - Orientation for Congressional visits (Box 547, Folder 12)
            - Congressional briefing (Box 547, Folder 13)
          - 1999 (Box 547, Folder 14)
          - 2000
            - General (Box 548, Folder 1)
            - Race Against Racism (Box 548, Folder 2)
        - Racial Justice Awards (at Convention)
          - General, 1984-91 (Box 548, Folder 3)
          - 1994: State/Regional Council winner: Pennsylvania Council of YWCAs application (Box 548, Folder 4)
          - 1996: nomination, Baton Rouge (Box 548)
          - Racial Justice Awards Dinner (fundraising gala), 1999
            - General, 1998-99 (Box 548, Folder 5)
            - Acknowledgments, 1998-99 (Box 548, Folder 6)
            - Corporate Award nominees, 1998-99 (Box 548, Folder 7)
            - Corporate Award: Federal National Mortgage Association ("Fannie Mae") (Box 548, Folder 8)
            - Invitations, 1999 (Box 548, Folder 9)
            - Sponsors, 1999 (Box 548, Folder 10)
            - 2000 (Box 548, Folder 11)
        - Statewide Days of Dialogue on Race Relations, 1998 (Box 548, Folder 12)
        - Stop Racism Youth Challenge, [see also National Day of Commitment to Eliminate Racism]
          - Steering Committee, 1999-2000 (Box 548, Folder 13)
          - Reference material: 'Racism Stop It!' program in Canada, 1998-2000 (Box 548, Folder 14)
          - 1999
            - General
              - Jan-Jul (Box 548, Folder 15)
              - Aug-Dec (Box 549, Folder 1)
            - Fundraising (Box 549, Folder 2)
            - Guidebook and publicity (Box 549, Folder 3)
          - 2000
            - General (Box 549, Folder 4-5)
            - Guidebook and publicity (Box 549, Folder 6)
            - White House Breakfast (Box 549, Folder 7)
          - 2001 (Box 549, Folder 8)
      - Public Affairs
        - Angela Davis trial, 1971-72 (Box 549, Folder 9)
        - Martin Luther King, Jr. Holiday, 1990-94, n.d. (Box 549, Folder 10)
        - School Busing, 1972 (Box 549, Folder 11)
      - Publications
        - General pamphlets, 1971-98 (Box 549, Folder 12)
        - Black Chronicle with discussion guide, 1971 (Box 549, Folder 13)
        - Career Planning for the Black Woman by Juanita Papillon and Elizabeth Morgan, circa 1972 (Box 549, Folder 14)
        - Voting is People Power, 1972 (Box 549, Folder 15)
        - Serials
          - The Barrier Breaker
            - 1972-75 (Box 549, Folder 16-18)
            - 1976 (Box 550, Folder 1)
          - On the Cutting Edge, Office of Racial Justice, 1987-89 (Box 550, Folder 2)
          - Racial Justice and Human Rights News and Views, 1998-2000 (Box 550, Folder 3)
      - Training
        - General, 1970-98, n.d. (Box 550, Folder 4-5)
        - National Institute on Administration, "Introducing Social Change: An Administrator Looks at Institutional Racism," Jan 1971 (Box 550, Folder 6)
        - Racial Justice Staff Development Program, 1987 (Box 550, Folder 7)
        - Racial Justice Leadership Seminar, 1989 (Box 550, Folder 8)
        - Mission Empowerment Process Facilitator's Manual, 1996 (Box 550, Folder 9)
        - Racial Justice Training Manual and 'How To' video, 1996 (Box 550, Folder 10-14)
  - Subseries D. Teenage and Younger Girls
    - General and History
      - General, 1919-97, n.d. (Box 551, Folder 1-2)
      - General brochures, 1907-85, n.d. (Box 551, Folder 3-4)
      - The Girl Reserve Movement of the Young Women's Christian Association: An Analysis of the Educational Principles and Procedures Used Throughout its History by Catherine S. Vance, 1937 (New York, NY: Columbia University Bureau of Publications) (Box 551, Folder 5)
      - "A History of the Girl Reserve Movement of the YWCA" by Mrs. Philip G. Eastwick, ca. 1931-32 (Box 551, Folder 6)
      - Anniversaries
        - Jubilee (1931)
          - Greetings from around the world (Box 551, Folder 7)
          - Correspondence re loan of greetings for exhibition (Box 551, Folder 8)
        - Sixtieth, 1941 (Box 551, Folder 9)
        - Centennial celebration, 1979-81 (Box 551, Folder 10)
      - Eight Week Clubs, 1913-19, n.d. (Box 551, Folder 11)
      - Memorabilia, insignias, uniform, etc., 1918-44, n.d. (Box 551, Folder 12)
      - National Teen Organization (NTO), 1973 (Box 551, Folder 13)
      - Rainbow Clubs, circa 1918 (Box 551, Folder 14)
      - YMCA-YWCA Cooperation, 1942 (Box 551, Folder 15)
    - Department and Committees
      - Correspondence
        - Miscellaneous, 1960-64 (Box 551, Folder 16)
        - Re revision of recruitment and membership pamphlet, 1982-83 (Box 551, Folder 17)
      - Membership notebook, May 1923 (Box 551, Folder 18)
      - Minutes
        - Girl Reserve Staff and Department (includes News-Letter,) 1914, 1917-18, 1920, 1922-31 (Box 552, Folder 1-10)
        - Girl Reserve Sub-Committee/Sub-Committee on the Teen-Age Program, 1935-52, 1959 (Box 552, Folder 11-17)
        - Teen-Age Program Committee, 1948-52, 1959 (Box 552, Folder 18-20)
        - Teen Empowerment Committee, 1973 (Box 552, Folder 21)
      - National Teen Council (NTC), 1988-2001 (Box 552, Folder 22-24)
      - News-letter to secretaries and advisers, 1929-30, 1946, 1975, 1994-98 (Box 553, Folder 1-2)
      - Younger Employed Girls, [see also Subseries A. Employed Women]
        - General, 1918-30, n.d. (Box 553, Folder 3)
        - Younger Girls in Business and Industry (YGBI), 1920-24 (Box 553, Folder 4)
        - Publications
          - "The Why and How of Leisure Time Activities Among Younger Employed Girls" by Zelah Heinbaugh, 1925 (Box 553, Folder 5)
          - "The Young Employed Girl" by Hazel G. Ormsbee, 1927 (Box 553, Folder 6)
          - "The Teenage Worker: In School and Out" and "And So To Work," 1943 (Box 553, Folder 7)
        - Report: YWCA work among younger employed girls by Helen McNeil, 1927-29 (Box 553, Folder 8)
      - Youth Constituencies Unit, 1974 (Box 553, Folder 9)
    - Conferences, Consultations, and Workshops
      - Conference planning guides, 1958, 1979, n.d. (Box 553, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous reports, 1925-31 (Box 553, Folder 11)
      - Adult Guidance Councils, 1926-31 (Box 553, Folder 12)
      - Branch Conferences, West Virginia Collegiate Institute, Institute, West Virginia, 1927-28 (Box 553, Folder 13)
      - Consultation on the Job Market and Career Development for Teen Women, 1974 (Box 553, Folder 14)
      - Consultation on Today's Teenagers, 14-15 Jan 1960 (Box 553, Folder 15)
      - Consultation on Work with Economically Deprived Adolescent Girls, 1966: report "Exploring Human Space," 1967 (Box 553, Folder 16)
      - Cultural Competency, Youth Development Workshop, Mar 1992 (Box 553, Folder 17)
      - High School Girl Reserve Mid-Winter Conference, 1924 (Box 553, Folder 18)
      - National Consultations on Teen Needs, 1981
        - Correspondence, planning, programs, press releases, 1981-82 (Box 554, Folder 1)
        - Evaluation forms
          - Dallas, TX (Box 554, Folder 2)
          - Des Moines, IA (Box 554, Folder 3)
          - Lancaster, PA (Box 554, Folder 4)
        - Reports (Box 554, Folder 5-6)
        - Transcript of tape recordings (Box 554, Folder 7)
        - Work Group reports
          - Community Service (Box 554, Folder 8)
          - Education (Box 554, Folder 9)
          - Employment (Box 554, Folder 10)
      - National Training School, 1930 (Box 554, Folder 11)
      - National Y-Teen Conferences, [see also Record Group 4. National Conferences and Conventions]
        - First, 1956 (Box 554, Folder 12)
        - Second, 1959 (Box 554, Folder 13)
        - Third, 1965
          - General (Box 554, Folder 14)
          - Reports, bulletins, and clippings (Box 554, Folder 15)
          - Remarks by Hubert H. Humphrey (Box 554, Folder 16)
        - National Y-Teen Assembly, 1982 (Box 554, Folder 17)
        - National Teen Assembly
          - 1988 (Box 555, Folder 1)
          - 1991
            - General, 1989-91 (Box 555, Folder 2)
            - Planning, 1990 (Box 555, Folder 3)
            - Priorities (Box 555, Folder 4)
            - Speakers and workshops (Box 555, Folder 5)
          - 1994 (Box 555, Folder 6)
          - 1996 (Box 555, Folder 7)
          - 1998
            - General and planning, 1997-98 (Box 555, Folder 8)
            - Packet for attendees (Box 555, Folder 9)
      - Staff
        - Verbatim report, 1922 (Box 555, Folder 10)
        - Findings of National Girl Reserve Staff Conference, April 1923 (Box 555, Folder 11)
        - Sep 1923 (Box 555, Folder 12)
        - Report of the Findings Committee of the Girl's Work Department Conference, Oct 1923 (Box 555, Folder 13)
        - 1924 (Box 555, Folder 14)
        - Summary, Apr-May 1925 (Box 555, Folder 15)
        - Minutes, Oct 1925 (Box 555, Folder 16)
        - Findings, Apr-May 1926 (Box 555, Folder 17)
        - Jun-Jul 1926 (Box 555, Folder 18)
        - 1927 (Box 555, Folder 19)
        - Apr 1928 (Box 555, Folder 20)
        - 1930 (Box 555, Folder 21)
        - 29 Dec 1939-5 Jan 1940 General and report "New Directions: Findings from the National Conference for Girl Reserve Secretaries" (Box 555, Folder 22)
        - 28 Dec 1950-3 Jan 1951 Report and abridged report "We Look Ahead: Findings of the National Conference for Teen-Age Program Directors" (Box 555, Folder 23)
      - Summer
        - Miscellaneous, 1929-31 (Box 556, Folder 1)
        - Sapphire, NC, 1930 (Box 556, Folder 2)
        - Camp Merrie-Woode, Sapphire, NC, 1932 (Box 556, Folder 3)
        - Camp Lookout, Golden, CO, 1943 (Box 556, Folder 4)
        - Camp Lookout, Golden, CO, 1945 (Box 556, Folder 5)
        - Comments on 16 Y-Teen Summer Conferences, 1949 (Box 556, Folder 6)
        - Southeastern, Blue Ridge Assembly Grounds, 1957 (Box 556, Folder 7)
        - "A Study of the Effect of the Interracial Aspects of the Program of Six Y-Teen Summer Conferences in the Southern Region on Girls Who Attended from 1958 through 1962" by Lillian H. Jackson (Box 556, Folder 8)
        - Report of the 1959 Y-Teen Summer Conferences and Supportive Adult Training in the Southern Region (Box 556, Folder 9)
        - Y-Teen Summer Conference Leaders' Institute, Central Region, 1960 (Box 556, Folder 10)
        - Report of Y-Teen Conferences in the Southern Region, Summer, 1962 (Box 556, Folder 11)
        - Tri-State Area Y-Teen Area Conference, Chatham College, Pittsburgh, PA, 1964
          - Conference packet (Box 556, Folder 12)
          - Planning Committee (Box 556, Folder 13)
          - Reports (Box 556, Folder 14)
          - Workshop materials (Box 556, Folder 15)
        - Report to the Field Foundation on Y-Teen Conferences in the Southern Region, Summer 1965 (Box 556, Folder 16)
        - Texas-Louisiana Y-Teen Summer Conference, Jun 1966 (Box 556, Folder 17)
    - Programs and Projects
      - General and miscellaneous, 1960-68 (Box 556, Folder 18)
      - Becoming a Woman workshops, San Francisco YWCA, 1982 (Box 556, Folder 19)
      - Juvenile Justice Program, 1978-81 (Box 556, Folder 20)
      - National Youth Service Day, 1998 (Box 556, Folder 21)
      - National Youthworker Education Project
        - General, 1976-80, n.d (Box 557, Folder 1-5)
        - Evaluation Conference, 12 Dec 1979 (Box 557, Folder 6)
        - NYEP Update, 1978-79 (Box 557, Folder 7)